You may well have heard of the term ‘spring cleaning’: the act of giving your house a deep clean in the spring months.
你很可能听过“春季大扫除”这个说法：指在春天对房屋进行一次彻底清扫的行为。
Even though, for many of us, that ritual of a once-a-year blitz of dirt and grime is dying out, some of us still practise it.
尽管对我们很多人来说，这种一年一度集中清理灰尘污垢的惯例已经渐渐被淡忘，但仍有人坚持这么做。
However, there could be a good reason the tradition isn’t as popular as it was.
不过，这个传统之所以不像过去那么流行，或许是有充分原因的。
The spring months are associated with new life and warmth – a stark contrast to the cold, gloomy winter that preceded.
春天总是和新生与温暖联系在一起——这与之前寒冷阴郁的冬天形成鲜明对比。
For protection against the freezing weather outside, people would seal their doors and windows as best they could to keep the heat in.
为了抵御室外的严寒，人们会尽可能把门窗封严实，好留住室内的热气。
In a time when many houses had fireplaces, open fires would churn out smoke and soot, coating rooms with layers of muck and gunk.
在过去，许多家庭都有壁炉，明火燃烧会产生大量烟尘，让房间里落满一层层的污垢。
It therefore made sense for people to start cleaning in the spring, when the weather was warmer and windows opened, to freshen up their houses, swabbing the floors and cleaning the walls.
因此，到了春天，天气转暖，窗户可以打开，人们便会着手打扫房屋，擦洗地板、清洁墙壁，让屋子焕然一新，这样做是很合理的。
However, open fires are no longer commonplace in modern British homes, with people preferring central heating to filthy smoke.
但如今，明火壁炉在英国家庭已经不常见了，相比污浊的烟尘，人们更青睐集中供暖。
And it’s not just the way of heating our homes that has changed.
而且改变的不只是供暖方式。
In the past, cleaning was designated to specific times and days, as simple chores like washing clothes took a long time.
过去，打扫卫生被安排在特定的时间和日期，因为就连洗衣服这种简单的家务，都要耗费很长时间。
The rise of gadgets such as the washing machine means that tasks are quicker and more efficient.
而洗衣机这类小电器的普及，让家务劳动变得更省时更高效。
However, psychologists such as Dr Jonathan Fader, argue that the mental health benefits of clearing the house of mess means that a spring clean is hugely positive.
但乔纳森·法德尔博士等心理学家认为，春季大扫除清理屋内杂物对心理健康大有裨益。
The perception of your house being cluttered can cause the stress hormone cortisol to rise.
当你觉得家里乱糟糟的时候，体内的压力荷尔蒙皮质醇水平会升高。
So, while the tradition is still there, and it’s nice to have a big purge of dirt once in a while, it is no longer as necessary – or limited to just the spring.
所以，尽管这个传统依然存在，偶尔进行一次全面的除尘清洁也确实不错，但它已经不再是必需的了——也不再局限于春天。
That said, the psychological benefits of having a tidy home means that a once-a-year purge of unnecessary items, rather than dirt, can make you feel much better.
话虽如此，一个整洁的家能带来心理上的愉悦感，因此每年清理一次不需要的物品，而非灰尘，也能让你心情舒畅不少。